[
    {
        "number": 1,
        "question": "A company operating in the AWS Cloud requires separate invoices for specific environments, such as development, testing, and production. <br/> How can this be achieved?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Use multiple AWS accounts",
            "B": "Use resource tagging",
            "C": "Use multiple VPCs",
            "D": "Use Cost Explorer"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 2,
        "question": "Which AWS service can be used in the application deployment process?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS AppSync",
            "B": "AWS Batch",
            "C": "AWS CodePipeline",
            "D": "AWS DataSync"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 3,
        "question": "What can be used to reduce the cost of running Amazon EC2 instances? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Spot Instances for stateless and flexible workloads",
            "B": "Memory optimized instances for high-compute workloads",
            "C": "On-Demand Instances for high-cost and sustained workloads",
            "D": "Reserved Instances for sustained workloads",
            "E": "Spend limits set using AWS Budgets"
        },
        "correct_answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 4,
        "question": "A company is launching an e-commerce site that will store and process credit card data. The company requires information about AWS compliance reports and AWS agreements. <br/> Which AWS service provides on-demand access to these items?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Certificate Manager",
            "B": "AWS Config",
            "C": "AWS Artifact",
            "D": "AWS CloudTrail"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 5,
        "question": "Which AWS service or feature allows the user to manage cross-region application traffic?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon AppStream 2.0",
            "B": "Amazon VPC",
            "C": "Elastic Load Balancer",
            "D": "Amazon Route 53"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 6,
        "question": "Which AWS service can be used to track unauthorized API calls?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Config",
            "B": "AWS CloudTrail",
            "C": "AWS Trusted Advisor",
            "D": "Amazon Inspector"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 7,
        "question": "A user needs to regularly audit and evaluate the setup of all AWS resources, identify non-compliant accounts, and be notified when a resource changes. <br/> Which AWS service can be used to meet these requirements?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Trusted Advisor",
            "B": "AWS Config",
            "C": "AWS Resource Access Manager",
            "D": "AWS Systems Manager"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 8,
        "question": "A user is planning to launch two additional Amazon EC2 instances to increase availability. <br/> Which action should the user take?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Launch the instances across multiple Availability Zones in a single AWS Region.",
            "B": "Launch the instances as EC2 Reserved Instances in the same AWS Region and the same Availability Zone.",
            "C": "Launch the instances in multiple AWS Regions, but in the same Availability Zone.",
            "D": "Launch the instances as EC2 Spot Instances in the same AWS Region, but in different Availability Zones."
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 9,
        "question": "A company must store critical business data in Amazon S3 with a backup to another AWS Region. <br/> How can this be achieved?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Use an Amazon CloudFront Content Delivery Network (CDN) to cache data globally",
            "B": "Set up Amazon S3 cross-region replication to another AWS Region",
            "C": "Configure the AWS Backup service to back up to the data to another AWS Region",
            "D": "Take Amazon S3 bucket snapshots and copy that data to another AWS Region"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 10,
        "question": "Which AWS Cloud service can send alerts to customers if custom spending thresholds are exceeded?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Budgets",
            "B": "AWS Cost Explorer",
            "C": "AWS Cost Allocation Tags",
            "D": "AWS Organizations"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 11,
        "question": "What is the recommended method to request penetration testing on AWS resources?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Open a support case",
            "B": "Fill out the Penetration Testing Request Form",
            "C": "Request a penetration test from your technical account manager",
            "D": "Contact your AWS sales representative"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 12,
        "question": "A user needs to automatically discover, classify, and protect sensitive data stored in Amazon S3. <br/> Which AWS service can meet these requirements?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon Inspector",
            "B": "Amazon Macie",
            "C": "Amazon GuardDuty",
            "D": "AWS Secrets Manager"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 13,
        "question": "Which components are required to build a successful site-to-site VPN connection on AWS? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Internet gateway",
            "B": "NAT gateway",
            "C": "Customer gateway",
            "D": "Transit gateway",
            "E": "Virtual private gateway"
        },
        "correct_answer": "CE",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 14,
        "question": "Which Amazon EC2 pricing option is best suited for applications with short-term, spiky, or unpredictable workloads that cannot be interrupted?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Spot Instances",
            "B": "Dedicated Hosts",
            "C": "On-Demand Instances",
            "D": "Reserved Instances"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 15,
        "question": "Which AWS cloud architecture principle states that systems should reduce interdependencies?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Scalability",
            "B": "Services, not servers",
            "C": "Removing single points of failure",
            "D": "Loose coupling"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 16,
        "question": "What is the MOST effective resource for staying up to date on AWS security announcements?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Personal Health Dashboard",
            "B": "AWS Secrets Manager",
            "C": "AWS Security Bulletins",
            "D": "Amazon Inspector"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 17,
        "question": "Which AWS service offers persistent storage for a file system?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon S3",
            "B": "Amazon EC2 instance store",
            "C": "Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS)",
            "D": "Amazon ElastiCache"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 18,
        "question": "Which of the following allows AWS users to manage cost allocations for billing?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Tagging resources",
            "B": "Limiting who can create resources",
            "C": "Adding a secondary payment method",
            "D": "Running all operations on a single AWS account"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 19,
        "question": "Which AWS service allows users to download security and compliance reports about the AWS infrastructure on demand?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon GuardDuty",
            "B": "AWS Security Hub",
            "C": "AWS Artifact",
            "D": "AWS Shield"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 20,
        "question": "Which of the following AWS services are serverless? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Lambda",
            "B": "Amazon Elasticsearch Service",
            "C": "AWS Elastic Beanstalk",
            "D": "Amazon DynamoDB",
            "E": "Amazon Redshift"
        },
        "correct_answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 21,
        "question": "Which AWS managed services can be used to extend an on-premises data center to the AWS network? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS VPN",
            "B": "NAT gateway",
            "C": "AWS Direct Connect",
            "D": "Amazon Connect",
            "E": "Amazon Route 53"
        },
        "correct_answer": "AC",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 22,
        "question": "Which requirement must be met for a member account to be unlinked from an AWS Organizations account?",
        "options": {
            "A": "The linked account must be actively compliant with AWS System and Organization Controls (SOC).",
            "B": "The payer and the linked account must both create AWS Support cases to request that the member account be unlinked from the organization.",
            "C": "The member account must meet the requirements of a standalone account.",
            "D": "The payer account must be used to remove the linked account from the organization."
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 23,
        "question": "What AWS benefit refers to a customer's ability to deploy applications that scale up and down the meet variable demand?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Elasticity",
            "B": "Agility",
            "C": "Security",
            "D": "Scalability"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 24,
        "question": "During a compliance review, one of the auditors requires a copy of the AWS SOC 2 report. <br/> Which service should be used to submit this request?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Personal Health Dashboard",
            "B": "AWS Trusted Advisor",
            "C": "AWS Artifact",
            "D": "Amazon S3"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 25,
        "question": "A company wants to set up a highly available workload in AWS with a disaster recovery plan that will allow the company to recover in case of a regional service interruption. <br/> Which configuration will meet these requirements?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Run on two Availability Zones in one AWS Region, using the additional Availability Zones in the AWS Region for the disaster recovery site.",
            "B": "Run on two Availability Zones in one AWS Region, using another AWS Region for the disaster recovery site.",
            "C": "Run on two Availability Zones in one AWS Region, using a local AWS Region for the disaster recovery site.",
            "D": "Run across two AWS Regions, using a third AWS Region for the disaster recovery site."
        },
        "correct_answer": "BD",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/startups/large-scale-disaster-recovery-using-aws-regions/>\n\n    Option D increased complexity and cost.",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 26,
        "question": "A company has a 500 TB image repository that needs to be transported to AWS for processing. <br/> Which AWS service can import this data MOST cost-effectively?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Snowball",
            "B": "AWS Direct Connect",
            "C": "AWS VPN",
            "D": "Amazon S3"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/storage/migrating-hundreds-of-tb-of-data-to-amazon-s3-with-aws-datasync/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 27,
        "question": "Which AWS service can run a managed PostgreSQL database that provides online transaction processing (OLTP)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon DynamoDB",
            "B": "Amazon Athena",
            "C": "Amazon RDS",
            "D": "Amazon EMR"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/rds/postgresql/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 28,
        "question": "Which of the following assist in identifying costs by department? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Using tags on resources",
            "B": "Using multiple AWS accounts",
            "C": "Using an account manager",
            "D": "Using AWS Trusted Advisor",
            "E": "Using Consolidated Billing"
        },
        "correct_answer": "AB",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 29,
        "question": "A company wants to allow full access to an Amazon S3 bucket for a particular user. <br/> Which element in the S3 bucket policy holds the user details that describe who needs access to the S3 bucket?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Principal",
            "B": "Action",
            "C": "Resource",
            "D": "Statement"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/walkthrough1.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 30,
        "question": "Which AWS service allows for effective cost management of multiple AWS accounts?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Organizations",
            "B": "AWS Trusted Advisor",
            "C": "AWS Direct Connect",
            "D": "Amazon Connect"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-organizations-policy-based-management-for-multiple-aws-accounts/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 31,
        "question": "A company is piloting a new customer-facing application on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) for one month. <br/> What pricing model is appropriate?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Reserved Instances",
            "B": "Spot Instances",
            "C": "On-Demand Instances",
            "D": "Dedicated Hosts"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/pricing/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 32,
        "question": "Which AWS tools automatically forecast future AWS costs?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Support Center",
            "B": "AWS Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) Calculator",
            "C": "AWS Simple Monthly Calculator",
            "D": "Cost Explorer"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/ce-forecast.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 33,
        "question": "Under the AWS shared responsibility model, which of the following is a responsibility of AWS?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Enabling server-side encryption for objects stored in S3",
            "B": "Applying AWS IAM security policies",
            "C": "Patching the operating system on an Amazon EC2 instance",
            "D": "Applying updates to the hypervisor"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/shared-responsibility-model/?ref=wellarchitected>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 34,
        "question": "A user is able to set up a master payer account to view consolidated billing reports through:",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Budgets.",
            "B": "Amazon Macie.",
            "C": "Amazon QuickSight.",
            "D": "AWS Organizations."
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/consolidated-billing.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 35,
        "question": "Performing operations as code is a design principle that supports which pillar of the AWS Well-Architected Framework?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Performance efficiency",
            "B": "Operational excellence",
            "C": "Reliability",
            "D": "Security"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/apn/the-5-pillars-of-the-aws-well-architected-framework/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 36,
        "question": "Which design principle is achieved by following the reliability pillar of the AWS Well-Architected Framework?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Vertical scaling",
            "B": "Manual failure recovery",
            "C": "Testing recovery procedures",
            "D": "Changing infrastructure manually"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/apn/the-5-pillars-of-the-aws-well-architected-framework/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 37,
        "question": "What is a characteristic of Convertible Reserved Instances (RIs)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Users can exchange Convertible RIs for other Convertible RIs from a different instance family with an equal or higher value than the Convertible Reserved Instances that you are exchanging.",
            "B": "Users can exchange Convertible RIs for other Convertible RIs in different AWS Regions.",
            "C": "Users can sell and buy Convertible RIs on the AWS Marketplace.",
            "D": "Users can shorten the term of their Convertible RIs by merging them with other Convertible RIs."
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ri-convertible-exchange.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 38,
        "question": "The user is fully responsible for which action when running workloads on AWS?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Patching the infrastructure components",
            "B": "Implementing controls to route application traffic",
            "C": "Maintaining physical and environmental controls",
            "D": "Maintaining the underlying infrastructure components"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 39,
        "question": "An architecture design includes Amazon EC2, an Elastic Load Balancer, and Amazon RDS. <br/> What is the BEST way to get a monthly cost estimation for this architecture?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Open an AWS Support case, provide the architecture proposal, and ask for a monthly cost estimation.",
            "B": "Collect the published prices of the AWS services and calculate the monthly estimate.",
            "C": "Use the AWS Simple Monthly Calculator to estimate the monthly cost.",
            "D": "Use the AWS Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) Calculator to estimate the monthly cost."
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/pricing-calculator/latest/userguide/aws-pc.pdf>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 40,
        "question": "Which are benefits of using Amazon RDS over Amazon EC2 when running relational databases on AWS? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Automated backups",
            "B": "Schema management",
            "C": "Indexing of tables",
            "D": "Software patching",
            "E": "Extract, transform, and load (ETL) management"
        },
        "correct_answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/Welcome.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 41,
        "question": "What does the Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering storage class offer?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Payment flexibility by reserving storage capacity",
            "B": "Long-term retention of data by copying the data to an encrypted Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) volume",
            "C": "Automatic cost savings by moving objects between tiers based on access pattern changes",
            "D": "Secure, durable, and lowest cost storage for data archival"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2018/11/s3-intelligent-tiering/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 42,
        "question": "A company has multiple data sources across the organization and wants to consolidate data into one data warehouse. <br/> Which AWS service can be used to meet this requirement?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon DynamoDB",
            "B": "Amazon Redshift",
            "C": "Amazon Athena",
            "D": "Amazon QuickSight"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/faqs/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 43,
        "question": "Which AWS service can be used to track resource changes and establish compliance?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon CloudWatch",
            "B": "AWS Config",
            "C": "AWS CloudTrail",
            "D": "AWS Trusted Advisor"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/evaluate-config.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 44,
        "question": "A user has underutilized on-premises resources. <br/> Which AWS Cloud concept can BEST address this issue?",
        "options": {
            "A": "High availability",
            "B": "Elasticity",
            "C": "Security",
            "D": "Loose coupling"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "<https://www.gremlin.com/blog/implementing-cost-saving-strategies-on-amazon-ec-2-with-chaos-engineering/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 45,
        "question": "A user has a stateful workload that will run on Amazon EC2 for the next 3 years. <br/> What is the MOST cost-effective pricing model for this workload?",
        "options": {
            "A": "On-Demand Instances",
            "B": "Reserved Instances",
            "C": "Dedicated Instances",
            "D": "Spot Instances"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 46,
        "question": "A cloud practitioner needs an Amazon EC2 instance to launch and run for 7 hours without interruptions. <br/> What is the most suitable and cost-effective option for this task?",
        "options": {
            "A": "On-Demand Instance",
            "B": "Reserved Instance",
            "C": "Dedicated Host",
            "D": "Spot Instance"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 47,
        "question": "Which of the following are benefits of using AWS Trusted Advisor? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Providing high-performance container orchestration",
            "B": "Creating and rotating encryption keys",
            "C": "Detecting underutilized resources to save costs",
            "D": "Improving security by proactively monitoring the AWS environment",
            "E": "Implementing enforced tagging across AWS resources"
        },
        "correct_answer": "CD",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2016/06/aws-support-enables-tagging-capabilities-for-trusted-advisor/>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 48,
        "question": "A developer has been hired by a large company and needs AWS credentials. <br/> Which are security best practices that should be followed? (Choose two.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "Grant the developer access to only the AWS resources needed to perform the job.",
            "B": "Share the AWS account root user credentials with the developer.",
            "C": "Add the developer to the administrator's group in AWS IAM.",
            "D": "Configure a password policy that ensures the developer's password cannot be changed.",
            "E": "Ensure the account password policy requires a minimum length."
        },
        "correct_answer": "AE",
        "explanation": "",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 49,
        "question": "Which AWS storage service is designed to transfer petabytes of data in and out of the cloud?",
        "options": {
            "A": "AWS Storage Gateway",
            "B": "Amazon S3 Glacier Deep Archive",
            "C": "Amazon Lightsail",
            "D": "AWS Snowball"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D",
        "explanation": "<https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/ug/transfer-petabytes.html>",
        "reference": ""
    },
    {
        "number": 50,
        "question": "Which service provides a user the ability to warehouse data in the AWS Cloud?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Amazon EFS",
            "B": "Amazon Redshift",
            "C": "Amazon RDS",
            "D": "Amazon VPC"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B",
        "explanation": "<https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/>",
        "reference": ""
    }
]